ANGELA B. LITTLE

(336) 749-3942 | ablittle209@outlook.com | Kernersville, NC | LinkedIn.com/in/angelablittle

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Application developer with 10+ years of experience successfully managing multiple projects simultaneously. Took career break for childcare and eldercare. Recent cybersecurity graduate with strong interest in returning to the paid workforce utilizing well-developed transferable skills and talents in a Cybersecurity Analyst role. Passion and aptitude for solving complex problems and applying new technology independently. Driven by new challenges and desire to excel in all endeavors. Dedicated to continued learning through daily practice in home lab, TryHackMe, and RangeForce platforms.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Languages: JavaScript, Java, Python, C#, Bash Scripting, PowerShell Scripting, SQL, C, C++
- Web Technologies: MS Visual Studio, ASP.NET, HTML, DHTML, ADSI, XML/XSLT, COM+, ODBC
- Database Management Systems: MySQL, Oracle, Microsoft Access
- Operating Systems: Windows, UNIX, Linux
- Tools: Nmap, Nessus, Wireshark, Burp Suite

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Cyber Security and Information Assurance

Western Governor's University | Salt Lake City, Utah

12/2021

- Capstone Project: "Implementing Zero-Trust Security to Secure a Remote Work Environment" Designed a security solution to mitigate risks by adopting a Zero Trust Security Framework to secure a perimeter-less corporate network, business critical applications, and data from cyberattacks based on the standards and concepts found in the NIST Special Publication 800-207, Zero Architecture.
- Relevant Coursework: Secure Software Design, Secure Network Design, Forensics and Network Intrusion, Cybersecurity Management, Ethical Hacking, Information Security and Assurance, Cybersecurity Architecture and Engineering
- Clubs and Organizations: WGU Cyber Club NCL Leadership Team, WGU Women in Technology

North Carolina State University | Raleigh, North Carolina

05/2017

• **Relevant Coursework:** Introduction to Computing – Programming Concepts with Java, Software Fundamentals Development – Advanced Java

Wake Forest University | Winston-Salem, North Carolina

05/1997

 Relevant Coursework: Discrete Mathematics, Linear Algebra, Calculus II, Data Structures, and Networking Essentials

Bachelor of Science in Management Information Systems

05/1992

University of NC at Greensboro | Greensboro, North Carolina

CYBER SECURITY COMPETITIONS

National Cyber League – Spring 2021 Season

Individual Game: (Bronze Bracket) National Rank: 2389/4180; Percentile: 43rd.

Bronze Bracket Rank: 644/2093; Percentile: 70th.

National Cyber League – Fall 2021 Season

Individual Game: National Rank: 1633/6478 Percentile: 75th.

Team Game (WGU Cyber Club | Team NERV): National Rank: 98/3910; Percentile: 98th.

CERTIFICATIONS

- CompTIA Security+ | CompTIA
- Certified Ethical Hacker (CEH) | EC-Council
- Certified Hacking Forensic Investigator (CHFI) -In Process (February 2022) | EC- Council

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Web Application Developer, Syngenta Crop Protection | Greensboro, NC

03/2001 - 04/2004

- Developed and maintained web-based applications for idea management, project planning, budgeting, and employee time tracking.
- Cultivated and maintained Visual Basic 6.0 console application to interface with SAP and export data into Oracle and SQL server databases.
- Enhanced and supported intranet application used for managing, shipping, and receiving research samples inventory.
- Conducted data manipulation and development of reports and report templates for different applications using Cognos Impromptu and MS Excel 2000 with VBA.

Application Developer, Inmar Enterprise | Winston-Salem, NC

09/1999-03/2001

- Designed, developed, and maintained a Coupon Management e-Business application using leading edge software and technology.
- Developed modules that enabled clients to retrieve and manipulate Coupon Promotions data based on complex criteria.
- Developed user friendly modules that allowed clients to personalize and format their webpage layout and information displayed on webpage.
- Developed COM components written in Visual Basic 6.0 using COM+ to manage and distribute the objects on Windows 2000 Advanced Server and Professional Platforms.

RELATED VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Volunteer OSINT Analyst, *Trace Labs*

06/2021

Participant in a Global OSINT search party CTF for real missing persons.

Coding Camp Instructor, *Habitat for Humanity of Forsyth County*

07/2020

 Developed and taught curriculum for the Youth Empowerment Program that introduced coding concepts and various programming languages for students in grades 7 – 12. Introduced students to career options in STEM.

PROFESSIONAL ASSOCIATIONS

Information System Security Association (ISSA)	12/2021 - present
Black Girls Hack (BGH)	01/2020 - present
Women in Cybersecurity (WiCyS)	12/2020 - present
Women in Technology International (WITI)	12/2020 - present